### Hugo A. Matilla Gómez

### Senior Android Developer

Address: Plaza Penuelas, 28005, Madrid Tel: 0034619037089

e-mail: hugo.matilla@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 27/01/1981 Nationality: Spanish web: <u>matgom.com</u>

### **OBJECTIVE**

To be part of the development team and to contribute to with my experience in Android developments, I.T. business and team work. I feel extremely motivated to continue improving my career in Android Applications development.

### **MY PROJECTS**

After almost four years working at Scondoo as main Android Developer and more than one year at SMF, I have been involved in many projects that are now in the Android Play Store. The duration of the developments I have worked on varied from 1 month to more than a year, and were undertaken both as solo projects and in teams. I also have formative experience in Windows Phone, iOS and JavaScript. Some of the Android projects that can be found in the store include: scondoo, HotUkDeals, reBuy, LernCoachies and DHL.

### **EXPERIENCE**

|   | LAFLRILITOL  |
|---|--|
| Android Developer<br>scondoo<br>Berlin/Remote. August. 2013 - Present | At scondoo I overtook with agility and speed the code developed by 2 different agencies. This code was in several cases unstructured. Thanks to my experience I improved it with ease, not only in performance but also in design.                                       |
| -   | Technical Skills: Android, Java, Kotlin, JSON, Git, JavaScript   |
| Android Developer  HotUKDeals  Berlin. Nov. 2014 – Feb.2015           | I worked remotedly with the HotUKDeals team in Canada building the new generic app, where I rapidly aquire the knowledge of the software architecture and the team methodologies to help them increase their development process.  |
|   | Technical Skills: Android, Java, Clean Architecture  |
| Android Developer Smart Mobile Factory Berlin. May. 2012 – July.2013  | My ability to quickly adapt to new concepts has been useful to develop and improve various Android Applications. Obstacles I must regularly overcome include definition changes, new features, improvements and tight deadlines.   |
|   | Technical Skills: Android, Java, JSON, XML, Windows Phone, Parse.  |
| Web App & ETL Developer Innova-TSN Madrid. Jan. 2011 - Feb. 2012      | I was quickly integrated in different projects, while experiencing new technical tools, supplying ideas and helping to find solutions. Additionally I assumed managerial and technical responsibilities, and regularly shared my expertise in Oracle with my colleagues. |
|   | Technical Skills: Java, JSP, Html, Css, Batch, C#, Oracle, Eclipse.  |
| ETL Developer AlamoConsulting   | I was part of a small team that developed a large scale corporate DataWarehouse, where versatility was a constant challenge.   |
| Madrid. Jul. 2009 - Dec. 2010   | Technical Skills: Oracle, SAS, SAS DIS   |

### **EDUCATION**

# Postgraduate Studies Mobile Development and Services

Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia

Madrid. Dec. 2010 - Jul. 2011

Main Subject Areas: Mobile Web and Android

Applications development.

Minor Subject Areas: Mobile technologies, history,

monetization, and IOS development.

Technical Skills: HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Java,

Android, Objective-C, IOS.

Main Subject Areas: Programming Methodologies, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Operating

Systems, Databases, Computer Architectures,

Minor Subject Areas: Digital Systems, Microcontrollers

Programming.

**Thesis:** Fairness and Market Based Techniques in Wireless Sensor Networks. Grade 1.3 (TU-Berlin).

## Computer Science Engineering MSc.

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Madrid. Sep. 1999 - Mar. 2009

### **LANGUAGES**

| English | TOEFL Score 94. December 2010. |
|---------|--------------------------------|
| German  | B2 Private School.             |
| Spanish | Mother Tongue.                 |

### I.T. SKILLS

| Languages               | Fluent: JAVA, Kotlin, JavaScript.  Basic: Swift, Python, Haskell               |
|-------------------------|--|
| WEB                     | Fluent: HTML5, CSS3, Nodejs.  Basic: React, Meteor, Polymer, WorPress, Jekyll. |
| Databases               | Fluent: SQLite, MongoDB, Oracle.  Basic: Realm, MySQL.                         |
| Operating Systems       | Fluent: OSX, Windows, Android.  Basic: UNIX, iOS.                              |
| Documentation           | Fluent: UML, E-R. Basic: Gantt.  |
| Agile                   | Fluent: Kanban, Scrum  |
| Version Control Systems | Fluent: Git  |

### **FURTHER INFORMATION**

- Erasmus Programme: TU-Berlin 2007-2009
- Tae-Kwon-Do and Muay Thay black belt.
- Mentor at CoderDojo
- More at <u>matgom.com/about</u>